Floyd S. Fierman papers, ca. 1850-1997 (bulk: 1870 - 1970)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Western Texas' Jewish History
  - Sabal family. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Form - (by the Oral History Project; 1979; interviewee was Matilde Sabal).
  - Sanger family. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Excerpt - Memorial and Biographical History of Dallas County, Texas (1892).
    Article - "A Letter of a Texas Pioneer, 1909" (by Morris Lasker), The Menorah Journal (Spring 1936; includes a letter from Morris Lasker to Mr. Sanger about business and family history).
    Letters from George Kohut to Sanger family (1902).
    "Isaac Sanger: From Texas...1914" (biography of Isaac Sanger).
    Article - "The Story of Sanger Bros.," Dallas Morning News (Sept. 17, 1949).
    Article - "The Story of Sanger Bros., Pioneer Retail Store of Texas," Southwest Jewish Chronicle.
    Brief biography of Lehman Sanger.
    Unidentified articles on the Sanger family.
  - Schick, Robert. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Story about him by his nephew, Joe Bamell - "The Violet Megaphone" (1988).
    Article - "Memories of My Life" (1988; Schick recalls experience in New York City and after).
  - Schlusselberg family: Brief genealogy of the Schlusselberg family (compiled by Fierman). (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Schoichet, Kopilowitz, and Brown (Wholesome Dairy of El Paso). (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Article - "Lithuanian Immigrant Fills Great Promise..." (about Lazar Kopilowitz).
    Genealogy of the Furman and Kopilowitz families.
    Clipping - (1980) award given to Bernard Schoichet.
    Articles on Kopilowitz family and the dairy industry and real estate.
    Clipping - (1960) on Wholesome Dairy.
    Fierman's notes on Litman Brown.
    Coba News, vol. XIV, no. 8 (October 1961; Ohio breeding association newsletter).
  - Schuster family. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Fierman's notes on the Schuster family.
    Article - "Eugenia Schuster Leaves Legend...," El Paso Times (May 12, 1981; on Michael and Eugenia).
    Obituaries for Bernard Schuster (June 1942).
    Clippings - on Schuster wedding anniversaries (1933-1941).
    Obituaries for Mrs. Bernard Schuster (August 30, 1949).
    Clipping - "Mrs. Bernard Schuster, Matriarch...85th Birthday" (Aug. 22, 1948).
  - Schutz family (various spellings of surname). (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Article - "Our Southwest Since American Settlement" (1920).
    Genealogy and notes by Fierman.
    Article - "Biographical and Historical Sketch of Mr. Samuel Schutz."
    Article - "Valley Club Announces Centennial Silver Tea In Old Schutz Place" (1936).
    Article - "Will Shutes Tells....," El Paso Times (1937; brief biography of Will Shutes).
  - Schwartz, Adolph. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Testimonial dinner (1924; on his tenure as president of the chamber of commerce).
    Letter - Irving Schwartz to Fierman on his writings on Adolph and family (Oct. 21, 1970).
    Fierman’s notes on A. Schwartz and Fanny A. Schwartz (from Ruth Zork and Irving Schwartz).
    Reminiscence on Adolph Schwartz written by Chris Fox and sent to Fierman (1978).
    Anecdotes of Adolph Schwartz (written by George Matkin to Fierman; 1978).
    Letter - (1978) M.B. Amstater to Ruth Zork.
    Letter - (1980) from Fierman (on the El Paso National Bank and Schwartz's involvement).
    Article - "Traveling Merchant is Great Store's Builder," El Paso Evening Post (May 30, 1928).
    Obituaries for Adolph Schwartz (1941).
    Clippings - on financial investments and philanthropic activity of Schwartz (1935-36).
    Clipping - marriage of Adolph Schwartz and Jennie Berg (1936).
    Last will and testament of Adolph Schwartz (August 6, 1938).
    Documents - on will of A. Schwartz (1941; appraisal of real estate).
  - Schwartz family. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Telegrams (24) - to and from (Maurice) Schwartz (1940; some to and from Budapest).
    Letters (59) - to Maurice Schwartz from Hungary (in Hungarian; 1939-40; some translated into English).
    Letters (47) - to and from M., Nandor, Sam, and Emanuel Schwartz (1940; some translated into English).
    Business letters - to and from Popular Dry Goods (1933, 1940).
    Letters (12) - Mendly to Nuchem (1939-40).
    Receipts from the Popular Dry Goods Dept. Store (1939-40).
    Edith Schwartz - "My Family" (December 19, 1962; Schwartz family history).
    Genealogy of the Schwartz family.
    Street maps which depict various property parcels.
    Clipping - (1981) on Maurice and Adolph Schwartz and their business and social ventures.
    Clipping - (1940) applauds Mayer Schwartz and classmates for superior posture.
    Clipping (1939) on dinner for Emanuel Schwartz and his fiancee, Ruth Ditch.
    Notes on family (source unknown).
    Notes on the Schwartz family used in Fierman's book entitled The Schwartz Family of El Paso.
    Letters to Fierman with regard to his book The Schwartz Family of El Paso (1980).
    Review of The Schwartz Family of El Paso in the El Paso Herald-Post (August 13, 1980).
  - Schwartz (Immigration and Naturalization Service). (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Letters - (1978) Immigration and Naturalization Service to Fierman (about Schwartz family).
    Adolph Schwartz's application for naturalization; Maurice Schwartz's alien registration form; documents about the location and date of entry of Adolph Schwartz into the United States.
  - Schwartz, Irving. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Fierman's manuscript on Irving Schwartz.
    Resume of Irving Schwartz.
    Testimony - Louis Bruce (Bureau of Indian Affairs) and Irving Schwartz.
    Document - about case of Hopi Indians vs. Peter MacDonald (1973).
    Letter - Peter MacDonald to Morris Thompson (with regard to Schwartz’s role as a consultant).
    Letters and statements (1970s; about Schwartz and the Bureau of Indian Affairs).
    Article - "Irving Schwartz Tells Plans to Retire June 1," El Paso Times (May 18, 1961).
    Handwritten map by Irving Schwartz of New Mexico.
    Letters of recommendation for Irving Schwartz's application for the U.S. Reserve Corps (1917).
    Notes written by Irving Schwartz for Fierman about background of the Schwartz family.
    Articles about Irving Schwartz's business career in creating markets for Indian products.
    Letters from Anne Moore to Fierman in regard to Irving Schwartz (1981).
  - Schwartz, James: Poetry written by James Schwartz (entitled "Exile of the Ineffable"). (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Schwartz Family, Maurice, E.H. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Obituaries for Maurice Schwartz (1954).
    Last will and testament of Maurice Schwartz (December 27, 1952).
    Fierman's notes on Maurice Schwartz.
    Article - (1978) from Hungarian News Agency, Budapest.
  - Schwartz (Popular Dry Goods). (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Charter for the A. Schwartz Company (1902).
    The Voice of The Popular; no. 1 (December 1925; published monthly by Popular Dry Goods).
    Discussion of the Popular Dry Goods Company, Inc. by Herbert Schwartz (August 10, 1978).
    Clipping - (1982) "The Popular: 80 Years of Border Growth" (about A. Schwartz and store).
    Popular Poppins (August 1978; bulletin for Popular store employees).
    Article - "New Distribution Center to Open," El Paso Times (August 8, 1975).
    Article about the building and operations of Popular Dry Goods Distribution Center.
    Article - "Story of the Popular Dry Goods Company" (by Kay Deaver; 1957).
    Articles about 50th anniversary celebration of Popular Dry Goods (1952).
    Letter - Henry Desenberg to Fierman (Feb. 18, 1980).
    Program for a cabaret dance performed for employees by the men's club of The Popular.
    Letter - Herbert Schwartz to Fierman (denies a proposed $6,000 grant from the Foundation; 1980).
    Article - "Popular Dry Goods Company Celebrates 50 Years of Growth" (September 1952).
    Nova: University of Texas at El Paso Magazine; vol. 13, no.2 (March 1978).
    Article - (1961) about the history and growth of the Popular Dry Goods Co.
    Bill of sale (February 1904).
    Obituaries for I. Weiss, manager of Popular Dry Goods Co. (1935).
    Article - "The Popular, Now 65, Grew With City of El Paso" (1967; source unknown).
    Letter - (1961) Deveryle Weiss to Fierman about Schwartz family and store.
  - Schwartz (rescue from Hungary). (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Letter - (1978) Mrs. Erich Spier to Fierman (on events in the exodus from Hungary during the 1940s).
    Letters from family members trying to escape Hungary (in Hungarian, with translations).
    Article by Fierman - about Schwartz family during the Holocaust; provides a discussion of Hungary before and during W.W.II, as well as Maurice and Nandor Schwartz's role in the rescue).
    Notes by Fierman during an interview with Leo Schwartz.
    Clipping - El Paso Herald-Post (1982; about Leo and Edith Schwartz' move to Israel).
    Documents and correspondence - (1939-40) about the Schwartz family leaving Europe.
  - Schwartz, Sam. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    Article - "Narrative For Historical Marker..." (biographical note on Sam Schwartz).
    Article -"Sam Schwartz: A Pioneer of the Theater Industry" (1974).
  - Schwartz (women in the family). (Box 7, Folder 30)
    Clipping - (1982) about the business executive Edi Brannon (daughter of Herbert Schwartz).
    Clipping about auction of sterling silver of Hedwig Mathias Schwartz.
    Articles - about Mrs. Maurice Schwartz's involvement in Temple Mt. Sinai (1936 to 1966).
    Notes - about roles of Georgie K. Schwartz and Ann S. Goodman in women's organizations.
  - Schwartz Family - Floyd Fierman. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Shwayder family: Article - (1964) provides history of Shwayder Bros. Grocery and the Shwayder family. (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Silberberg, Abraham: Clippings - El Paso Times (April 26, 1934; A. Silberberg's connection with El Paso). (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Silver, Necha: Notes - interview compiled by the Oral History Project (1979; genealogy of the Silver family). (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Simon family. (Box 7, Folder 35)
    Letter - (1983) Evelyn Fox to Fierman (requests his book on Jews of El Paso).
    Letters - (1982) Marion Simon Garmel to Fierman (trip to Israel and family history).
    Clipping - (1981) about Sam Simon and his role as a consumer advocate.
    Genealogy of the Simon family (compiled by Fierman).
    Clipping - (1982) about Sam Simon's role as a consumer advocate.
  - Smith, Joe H.: Letters - (1963-64) Smith to Fierman (information on Frank and Charles Sperling). (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Snyder, Mike. (Box 7, Folder 37)
    Letter - (1980) Morris A. Galatzan to Fierman (about Jacob Snyder).
    Fierman's notes on the Snyder family (June 10, 1980).
  - Spier/Behrend families. (Box 7, Folder 38)
    Article - "Family Chronicle" (by Itzig Behrend; Germany; ca. 1829; intro. by W. Bonwitt; 1978).
    Article - "A Message to Werner Spier..." (by Fierman; about the Spiers).
  - Stein, Aaron: Obituary for Aaron Stein. (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Strickland, Rex W.: Article - "My Love Affair with the Mesilla Times" (about the New Mexico newspaper). (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Temple Beth El (Corsicana, TX): Article - (1990) about group who save Temple Beth El (includes photographs). (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Temple Mount Sinai: Article - "The Eternal Light and the Cross" (by Fierman; about new temple building). (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Texas history: Population study - (El Paso; 1836-1905) compiled by El Paso Public Library. (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Texas Jewish Historical Society. (Box 7, Folder 44)
    Texas Jewish Historical Society Newsletter (Austin, TX; 1986, 1989-90,1993-1997).
    Letter - Society to A. Chanin (1989).
  - Zielonka, Rabbi Martin. (Box 7, Folder 45)
    Article - "Martin Zielonka: Rabbi..." (1982).
    Letters - (1957-58) Martin Zielonka to Evelyn Rosen (with regard to his father).
  - Additions. (Box 7, Folder 46)
    The Spiegelbergs: Pionner Merchants and Bankers in the Southwest, by Floyd Fierman
    Early Jewish Settlers.
    Zeckendorfs
  - Hertzog Working Papers. (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - The Spectacluar Zeckendorfs Fierman, Floyd S., The Journal of Arizona History, Winter, 1981. (Box 7, Folder 48)